Sabrina Kent Artificial Intelligence / Machine Learning Engineer

sabrinabythesea@yahoo.com 262-490-1197 github.com/sabrinabythesea

Professional Summary

I'm a machine learning engineer with an M.S. in artificial intelligence as well as extensive supplemental education gained through online courses (MIT Open Courseware, UC-Berkeley, deeplearning.ai, coursera.org). Fluent in Python, R, and Java, I have significant machine learning experience with standard algorithmic techniques and neural networking as well as time-series forecasting, physics-based modeling, and research-informed feature generation. I am dedicated to being an active, fully-engaged participant in my own life, to asking the right questions, and to embracing risks – because comfort with exploring new ideas and with stretching one's abilities will always be at the heart of emerging technologies. I am motivated by curiosity, puzzle-solving, and a deep desire to never stop learning. With 13+ years of practical and theoretical computer science experience, I excel at both self-directed work and highly structured collaborative projects with detailed requirements and strict deadlines.

Technical Experience

Technical Skillset: Keras, TensorFlow, Trax, TensorFlow.js, TensorFlow Lite, Python, Java, R, SQL, Javascript, Linux, Ruby.

Analytics Skillset: Deep Neural Networks, Recurrent Neural Networks, Residual Networks, Convolutional Neural Networks, Time Series Forecasting, XGBoost, Random Forest, Regression, Classification.

Theoretical Skillset: Sequence Models, Natural Language Processing, Machine Translation, Neural Style Transfer, Object Detection, Facial Recognition, Al-based Autocorrect, Part of Speech Tagging, Autocomplete, Word Embeddings, Decision Theory, Probability Logic.

Sabrina Kent sabrinabythesea@yahoo.com 262-490-1197

Professional Experience

Foxconn Industrial Internet - Milwaukee, WI Artificial Intelligence / Machine Learning Engineer Dec 2019 - Apr 2020

- Collaborated within a small self-directed team to provide AI modeling services for both external and internal clients.
- Evaluated various machine learning algorithms for solving individual project needs
- Developed performance metrics for comparative analysis
- Performed research-informed feature generation
- Met specific goal timelines while maintaining a commitment to dependably accurate results
- Communicated with other teams and clients with various levels of technical knowledge

Nationwide Insurance - Columbus, OH Data Science Intern May 2017 – Aug 2017

- Wrote large SQL query for merging 50+ MS Excel tables with non-matching features
- Converted SQL query to Jupyter Notebook based Python script for greater efficiency and reusability
- Produced Unix-based scripts for automating common team tasks
- Developed series of Test-Driven Development Kata programs

Beachdog.com - Long Beach, WA Project Manager, Web Developer Jan 2007 – Jan 2012

- Acted as sole liaison between clients and tech department
- Developed and maintained crucial customer relationships
- Balanced design team resources with technical requirements and client timelines
- Implemented new office-wide project tracking system
- Reduced staffing needs by 35% through task streamlining initiatives
- Used CSS, HTML, and Photoshop within the WordPress environment

Espy Foundation - Oysterville, WA Director

Mar 2006 – Jan 2007

- Managed non-profit residency program for writers and artists
- Took on marketing and web development responsibilities
- Decreased operations budget by 20%
- Reallocated budgeted resources to increase residencies awarded per term

Personal Projects

Twitter Analysis of Lupus-related Tweet Subtopics

- R coding language
- Collected and filtered tweets labeled with #lupus using rtweet package
- Evaluated patterns in keyword frequencies to determine use of twitter for symptom discussions among lupus patients
- Converted code development and findings into an R Markup based reporting document available at https://github.com/sabrinabythesea/lupus/blob/master/LupusSymptomsTwitter.pdf

Modeling Amino Acids as Robots for Optimization of Antibody Peptide Active Sites

- Combined robotics motion planning techniques with biochemical and immunological research
- Explored analogous factors between biomolecules and electric-field-based / magnetic singlearmed robots
- Developed theoretical system for expanding on preliminary research to create an Al-based medical development tool

Survey of Linquistic Tools for RNA sequence-structure correlation

- Researched linguistic development of multiple context free grammars (MCFGs)
- Collected research on RNA pseudoknots and difficulties they pose to sequence-based structure prediction
- Connected MCFG concepts to their use in RNA pseudoknot prediction and explored related open problems

Education & Honors

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee MS Artificial Intelligence 2020

University of Wisconsin - Madison BS Molecular Biology 2003

Wisconsin Advanced Opportunity Fellow 2017-2019

Certifications

Neural Networks and Deep Learning Specialization
https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/9862GVDR7DB6

TensorFlow: Data and Deployment Specialization
https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/F9A2NENSJ9MJ

DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer Specialization https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/RUE6DUEZ94RW

DeepLearning.AI Natural Language Processing Specialization https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/MND8LC29DKSX